

Tajalli Shareef (CHRP)

Assistant Manager Compensation and Benefits at BDO Ebrahim Consulting (Pvt.) Ltd.

Address №: Near Sir Syed Girls College, Nazimabad No. 1, and Karachi, Pakistan. \$\mathbb{L} + (92)307-7970596

Skye ID: <u>TajalliShareef</u>

☑ tajallishareef@gmail.com

⇔ LinkedIn Profile

Field of Interest: -

✓ Recruitment and Selection | ✓ HRBP | ✓ HR Operations & Payroll | ✓ Compensation & Benefits | ✓ Training and Organizational Development

Career Summary: -

Strategic HR professional with 10+ years of experience in Compensation & Benefits, Payroll, and HR Operations across multinational clients and diverse sectors. Proven record of accomplishment in streamlining HR processes, ensuring statutory compliance, and driving process automation.

Professional Experience: -

BDO Ebrahim Consulting (Private) Limited



BDO is a Pakistan registered partnership firm and are members of BDO International Limited, a UK company limited by guarantee, and form part of the international BDO network of independent member firms. Our clients are JLL Pakistan, Lenovo Pakistan, Signify (Philips) Pakistan, Turbo Systems Pakistan, Dutch Embassy of Netherlands, Bloomberg Pakistan, Maersk Pakistan, Xiaomi Pakistan, AWAL Telecom, Avient Corporation & JC Penney Pakistan, GFK Etilize, L'Oreal Pakistan etc.

Deputy Manager - HR Compensation & Benefits From 07^h January 2022 till date

Job Responsibilities:

- ✓ Led a team in managing payroll operations for 900+ employees across local and international clients, ensuring accuracy and compliance.
- ✓ Developed HR policies and compensation structures, aligning with business goals and industry standards.
- ✓ Spearheaded process automation, reducing payroll errors by 15% and enhancing efficiency.
- ✓ Validated performance-based pay, bonuses, and deductions while implementing payroll checks that reduced errors by 15%.
- ✓ Processed payroll through direct deposits and bank portals, generating and distributing payslips via employee portals.
- ✓ Submitted income tax, EOBI, and SESSI payments while ensuring compliance with government regulations.
- ✓ Coordinated EOBI registrations, benefit provider payments, and retirement fund contributions.
- Reviewed payroll reports for finance, HR, and audit purposes, ensuring accuracy and reconciliation.
- ✓ Developed HR policy manuals, employee handbooks.
- ✓ Provided strategic guidance on income tax, labor laws, and regulatory compliance, strengthening clients' HR frameworks.
- Mentored junior HR professionals, fostering skill development and process ownership.

Qualification: -

- ✓ MPhil in Human Resource Management | KASB Institute of Technology (KASBIT) | 2020 – 2022 Thesis: Effects of Supportive Work Environment & Training on Employee Retention in Textile Industry
- ✓ MBA in HR Management | KASB
 Institute of Technology (KASBIT) | 2012
 2014
- ✓ B.Com | Premier College | 2011

Achievement: -

- ✓ 1st Position CHRP Program at NED University
- ✓ 2nd Position MBA (HR) from KASBIT

Job Fairs: -

- ✓ Attended Job Fair & Final Year Students Project Exhibition at Sir Syed University on the part of Modest Solutions in January 2018
- One Day spent in Job Fair on the Part of Feroze1888 Mills Ltd held at Expo Centre exhibition named "Career & Education at Expo" dated 24May 2014 for the purpose of Employer Branding.
- ✓ One Day spent in Job Fair on the Part of Feroze1888 Mills Ltd held at Bahria University dated 15Dec,14
- ✓ One Day spent in On Campus Talent Driving on the part of Feroze1888 Mills Ltd held at NED University of Engineering & Technology on October 2015.

Professional Experience: -

Acme Mills (Pvt.) Ltd.



Acme Mills is a vertically integrated textile unit, from weaving to stitching. They manufacture fabrics and made-ups for Institutional, Home Textiles and Apparel Industry and export to different countries.

HR Executive - Generalist Role

From 8th July 2019 to 05th January, 2022

Job Responsibilities:

- ✓ Managed end-to-end recruitment, onboarding, and talent acquisition strategy to improve workforce quality.
- Managed payroll processing through ERP software, ensuring accurate attendance and overtime tracking.
- Created HR policies, updated JDs, and maintained employee records & compliance reports.
- Led payroll processing & audits, ensuring zero discrepancies and compliance with labor laws.
- ✓ Implemented performance management initiatives, improving retention and engagement.

Eternal Group of Industries (PIPE PLUS & Vida

pipe plus

Ceramics)

A state of the art manufacturer of building and construction material and Importer of Ceramics

Admin Executive

From 27th August 2018 to 6th July 2019

Job Responsibilities:

- ✓ Managed logistics, delivery coordination, and client relations.
- ✓ Processed quotations, invoices, and material returns.

Certificate: -

- ✓ Certified Human Resource
 Professional (CHRP)| PIQC
 Institute of Quality & NED University
 |Jul Oct (2024)
- ✓ Certificate in Information
 Technology (CIT) Technical
 Training Centre for Women (2009)
- Presentation Skills Training (2014)
- ✓ Stress Management Workshop (2016)
- ✓ Fire Fighting Training (2014)

Languages: -

- ✓ English (Fluent)
- ✓ Urdu (Native)

Technical Skills: -

- ✓ Payroll Processing & Tax and Compliance Management
- ✓ Compensation Benchmarking
- ✓ Payroll Software (ERP, TimeTrax)
- ✓ Labor Law Compliance
- ✓ HR Policy Development
- ✓ Process Automation
- ✓ MS Office Suite: Excel (Pivot Tables, VLOOKUP etc.), Word, PowerPoint

Professional Experience: -

Modest Solutions



Modest Solutions provides expert outsourced HR Consultancy and support to local as well as international clients. Our clients are Nisum Technologies, Banklslami Pakistan, Jamjoom Pharma, Hilton Pharma, Saakh Group, Shan Foods & Harley Willington group of companies.

Senior HR Executive - HR Generalist

From 30th October 2017 to 24th May, 2018

Job Responsibilities:

- ✓ Delivered full HR services for Airmen Golf Club.
- Managed payroll, organizational structures, and policy development.
- ✓ Assisted in talent sourcing and executive search for local & international clients.
- ✓ Dealing with EOBI and SESSI related matters

Feroze1888 Mills Ltd



Formerly Feroze Textile Industries (FTI), Leading manufacturers and exporters of specialized Textile Terry Products in Pakistan

HR Business Partner

From 25th April, 2013 to 28th October, 2017

Job Responsibilities:

- ✓ Led recruitment, training & development, and performance appraisals.
- ✓ Conducted grievance handling and disciplinary actions.
- ✓ Managed annual appraisal cycles & career planning initiatives.
- ✓ Handling Annual Appraisal Cycle
- ✓ Doing post Appraisal working i.e. Training Need Evaluation (TNA), Career plans, and placements of key players
- ✓ Worked on different OD projects